Have radium perspire accreditation to milk over
...okay height welcome you guys
...this last session of build twenty fifteen relief meaningful...guys...come out
and make it and I'm surprised by how many people are actually here robin I kind of...around a little bit
...it was can...us and basically just the janitor ready to kick us out of
...presentations...coming out where really excited
...share with you what we've been doing?
My name is what reed and this is rob
...just introduced as you can see I'm a visual designer I've worked with a
tundra...my life and I have to tell you I love working with you guys you guys make
everything that I work on...and you bring the life to it...he so, much for that and,
I know you guys work really hard and...put a lot of...into the...you...you know,
to create experiences that designers one or, you know,
to create the experiences of your actual apps of reduced and, you know,
just thinking about that the space and all
that snares is just the question of
...be great if there was actually something out there that major life easier that there
was something that you could quickly, you know, to build from or build on
...you could actually tailor the experiences that you're working towards or create those, you know,
ideal experiences you want I'm sure we'd all agree that we'd love to see that and
have that opportunity as well greatthanks my name is rob
cameron I was on the xbox team for the...many teams microsoft most
recently the xbox team for three years and I've just recently joined the ad eecs
...engineering team in the developer experience group and what we do is we work with a
...to of saha problems for you and have
make your life easier is our goal please do take photoshop a shot
...code and get the...actually...to get your feedback in your feedback please let us know it
...things you want to do or what tampered template you want to see us work on next
with other get your feedback so please of thought the survey just a tiny bit of background as I
...work on xbox in the app program
...with xbox three sixty so who's why some media app on xbox three sixty yeah,
a whole bunch hands go up and said I kind of expected...of those
album the majority of those apps are build in with the reference app is what we call
...the time this app is build a csharp and sam...was the first-time ability and apple
...bringing the app platform to xbox we had a very high bar very
focus design targets for what we wanted our partners to hit and it
was very successful for the next step in that evolution was
the xbox one for xbox one we said we into a reference app we did a mediad
...media template are media sample?
That sample is...js all the apps we spoke about this last year build all
the apps on xbox one are written in
no-win js we took we learn from...three sixty and we evolved
...we made a more...the media template on xbox
...that all the app the majority of apps uses a starting point and
build on from that it is an app it has a good architecture and
oga sound design for sure what...we didn't add a lot of extra code in
air we kind of want to you to be able to see the api...experience api
...in easily customize in modified sofast for now to the
universe windows platform and that's really what we're going to be focusing on for the rest of our talk?
that leads to where we are today which is the jury just begins with you guys we're all in the
...together as far as what were taking the actual universal media are
...universal windows platform and leveraging across the different devices
I rahman are really happy to share with you what we've been working on and building towards
which will be illustrated in...box on
...mobile and desktop but, you know, as we
...the future of the across all devices so I'm really excited to introduce
...thing work for me seomark
...is...universal windows media sample and
...really cool great thing is that it is available on wednesday asks and on sample as
well now what is the actual sample what is what's entailed it's basically a
...app...edge that you can leverage
and use and ideally it's really just make it easier for you
to build on easier to get started which basically means that it
...you time so you can get to market faster and ultimately
it means you can create the amazing experiences you really want to and it's not
just for one group it's actually created for designers as well as
our developers and we wanted to be for everyone all creators throughout the world?
So, what is actually included in?
The first...go through the...primary patterns that jeff and
...illustrated before while we're going to focus on just one today
I want to let-you know that we are working on trying to creepy samples for each one of
these so in the future...able to leverage all of them across all devices.
So, today we're going to focus on the hub is
are primary control throughout the entire media sample?
Nowit's one of my favorite controls and the
reason why is because it has a wonderful flexibility and,
it's not just one-in-one orientation but to...previously before we had in just
...you know,...and be able, you know, kind of panned through but,
after getting much feedback from a lot of different groups we actually
create with a secondary orientations getting even more flexibility in capability as far as
what you want actually leverage for your application in addition to that we also have
big into it in the section...that you also have panning
inc so, for example, a vertical model that would have scrolling you can have horizontal panning
inc and vice versa if you're in horizontal kind of a page
layouts so gives you even more flexibility as far as where you...actually take it beyond that.
In the sample itself there's four primary pages
...included...being home.
Gallery.
Details and also the media transfer control or as
I like to call mtc just something I've learned to...the time so if you hear me say that
the relatively transfer control.
It also am is included in the sample rtwelve controls which are the hub the list
...view the push buttonmedia transfer control grid
...scroll control combo box flip
...text box ratings and backbone.
So, now we're going to like literally...the term kindness
...the hiding take a look at what...actually the sample consist of.
Ok,
so, home is really kind of your hero and, should really entice user especially
in app of this type where content truly is king home should be the
...defines in a clear what the actual app is
after a long of research and looking around...different app models and how they're handling stuff
nobles internally and externally we want-to make sure you guys had the flexibility
...opportunity across
the home experience so, you by not new as far as what the actual
...page displays and has a lot of flexibility...we want you to
...the you have the ability to mix and match and re kind of
transform the actual page to bessie your needs?
If we take a deep...really look at what it actually has included in the page
there's the split seo course inc...
We have list views both in horizontal and vertical.
As well as a flip view or most commonly known as the carousel.
We also added in addition
inline mtc which wasn't previously inc and but it
...like a great opportunity for you guys to play with that as well and have in your system so,
for easy access for your users to use?
And,...will jump into the actual...give you a look...
So, here's a template running on windows.
And,...talk through the template as we school
...down ok so on the top left cordon quadrants, you know,
so, there's actual placement for brandy we want-to make sure you had the opportunity
branching accordingly so you can choose to incorporate images...whatnot to have
...in we've also added in the hammer button as
...affectionately...called throughout this entire build conference inc
...there too we also had the horizontal listed is my...currently
in here as well as a see all for you'd have kind of like a spill over
of content which would take you to details paid era of gallery pager whatnot depending
on your need and how you want to place it this next...showing the carousel and,
how that kind of works really well for that we're trying to create a blend between
...prominent arianna top that was just one single images a hero three-one to
just have that or if you want to have other sub sections as well that would allow you to have, you know,
kind of...carousel element inc below that were showing
an example of the movies from section which is using the...box
...in here we've incorporated throughout the template to give you guys a better
base to build off different assets sizes
...not structure just one you can have a flexibility kind of just like take it and run with it in
...here is another...carousel...is while
...in here and then if we scroll down showing just a typical one by one or,
you know, a tv boxer assets as well in
...list view and then below is a sneak peek we
...give a lot of prominence at least for the visual q for what we displayed on us one
for an inline video?
Ok, so, now...jump into gallery gallery to me is really
kind of the workhorse of an app, you know, it's an intense browsing or,
you know, generally are kinda in the mode of let me see what all my options are, you know,
we looked at the use of...to make sure they were getting greater flexibility and right now
we're illustrating just one of the asset types by to
know that when we actually give out's...to you will have guidance to help you
guys spurs know the many different aso type types throughout.
the gallery consists of the following elements in there one being the review.
And, then also there is the combo box and you notice I have
to elements laid on top of each other one is referencing will be used on
mobile pc and the other one illustrates how will actually look at
...box and when we jump into the demo I can explain the differences
...were catering a little bit different?
...different staff.
Some navigate home page once again ever focus on a gallery so we have the see all
button social with the lists.
...see you have a very calming kind of place layout in what you'd expect
for most galleries and we have inc for the example of showing a
pc can see how it kind of transitions and...appropriately as far as the amount of content puts
where boxes available and we have the...of the combo box aka
filters of the top those of course are sticky and work really well in the environment of a
phones pc scenario so it it's very common place and it's
greatest first as a base to get you started also have...narrowed the title as well but you can kind of
...cater appropriately...the switch to have four.
...kind of becoming your van I think a little bit more.
Looser button pushing.
Some...navigate down on the app to the see all button for the new movies
list running on phone.
So, I will quick see all here.
...lenin lynette mention the
...sorter sticky at the top says...scroll a remain completely invisible for
...obviously smaller that's a single-line are no extra code to make this run
on phone as you saw when I was running on pc that's why I did as
I strongly screen down the...the...outages
...the code down the ui down to this single lane...
the single column rather...the running on pc or running on phone...switch two-x...
So, here's the abrogated here is the same application running on xbox.
Will spend more time on xbox?
...show the gallery.
Which the reason that we went with this model is simply because of
...and playing with them for the orientation as far as being able to click-through content the
of easy access point there's only, you know, three actual items...bump over with
...controller to be able to quickly access the filter if we were to try to
...how it is...you run into some issues as far as having the lack of
stiki headers which means you have to incorporates some kind of button
association mapped to it to work appropriately so, just for ease of use
we want with this model just to get out there for everyone to use more easily but, you know,
as considerations and other additional options become available of course
...overall roll-out more models as well.
Ok, now to run
...details a and to me the details is
...pump it sorry pardoning and jumping a little head-on my controller.
To me the details pages really the information keeper or the oracle of
a page in app it's kind of that final decision maker as far as for user
and, you know, if they want to make one of those split-second decisions on if it's yasser
...one actually get a watch, you know, content or move forward with something
small it definitely gives the appearance of being more light-weight and it definitely is
...majority of the time is a heavy hitter and...a lot of content within it.
And, today I'm going to focus on showing...the tv details version we do also have
...in...movies details you have
...flexibility of either to re purpose...the details pages self course
you have a ratings ...in their attacks box control.
Is also push button?
Horizontal, you know, list views inc.
And, we also incorporated in here and the vertical list views
now the cool thing on the vertical list views is that we
inc different options as far as the actual elements the build-up
...list so you have bowls and image one it can be
utilized as well as one this just text itself or one
...numeral elements as well as a progression bar so it gives you a little bit
...greater flexibility as far as how you want to users elements incorporate them throughout.
Will jump into the...on that one?
We go moi.
Content.
So, you can see it has a prominent here of course...in
there we have the different elements as far as the rating and try to...
Okay,
and, then it also has, you know,...button control elements in...as well.
Below that we've put...of an actual episodes list
...not shown in herein is getting currently built-in there is the filters you're able to actually
filters are content on-the-fly in the actual page versus having to drill down to separate elements and
you guys can use that for any possible...orientation you need.
And, then of course if the list of segment avert
...orientation shown here.
And, of course the additional list items represented in a sixteen
nine format as well as within...boxer format so one thing wanted to
...washear is the act creator section which is wide for
running on the desktop or the or xbox one
...you switch to four and we'll get to the phone?
Me hit back.
...down to it...tv section.
Oops go back hit play...there.
Thanks...I do...something over here.
Ok.
There's a lot of buttons up here
...demos going on a lot of different platforms over there with this version accent.
Me we try this real quick.
See this works.
And,...manager...yet...
Ok, the switch...pc.
Have a back-up?
In here is the contest me application.
I go back down to tvs.
And,...is not cooperating okay I have a third back-up sang with me.
I'm determined to show you these demos you will
not relent until we get them up here so let me heavy emulator spun up.
...go and I will...to do deploy to
...I face so make may take a second what we can do is.
Samoa.
...and, lines.
Okay,... gamy let's...
can need continue and I'll work on this little bit and then I will pick it up and hope that's a good luck term.
...that means everything else can...have one little snafu.
Okay, well,...took the phone...is exciting ratio
...show he showed okay this huge
...ok so I'll jump in and media transfer controls...
...media transfer control courses the foundation of a and,
...most important element of a...of assert being that...media type is kind of an over
...kinda gotta have that otherwise it's not really and media capital what
...looked a lot of different media transfer controls that were out
there from other applications as walls what's been adjusted for xbox as well as,
you know, other windowsdevices and wanted-to make sure that we were providing the
best fame for you guys throughout the system so I'm really happy to tell you
that instead of having just one the actual media a transfer control type
...actually giving you too ...the same items you have a single
online media transfer control which means that has the buttons and describer
than additional buttons as well as a double
...and media transfer control which means that you have the actual scarborough on top
and buttons below it which gives greater flexibility depending on
me environment you're trying to design for what you're trying to covers person.
So, it within the app sample...hero
...lead of...someone to go through a little bit of the actual...are baked in their elements
...there...you guys can use and how to use them appropriately?
...we have.
The time scrub are the times cover we
want-to make sure you guys can actually incorporate branding within their so the
...indicated to the left there that's...read you can actually change according to whatever you
need for brands and if you want to choose to use that the way it's based on the
actual windows platform where they're using user color that's totally fine but if you want to...make
itexclusively pertaining to your actual brand...giving the freedom to do that
in addition to that which is not illustrated here we've incorporated in for
life feeds so the placement of the line to the right
...will actually load and to indicate with a little bit darker
...bar and than a later one will come over to show as far as what the actual libra
...that incorporated in there.
We also have the time...stamp which is a no-brainer
...that in order for media transfer control the work.
And, also we have buttons
...in here we've instilled within the actual code
...of spaces in between the different buttons so that you have the flexibility to
add additional buttons as you need per your actual application as well as
a customization to be able to change them accordingly to what you need a there's a babysat
...and there which can freely we use as well?
And, another element is the post...and getting on
a feedback the logical wanted one or lisa guidance or something help and...happy to tell
...you also get a post role baked and there as well as...just really...of what you doing.
Is still networking propagated...behavior cooking with gals ok?
So, let's jump...what you want to look at the other...do...do measure control...the pc.
So, can switch to ...
Some say this is lynette favored video of all time
...laos this video uses video because who...xbox...their time
...the developer pastime if you...out...this very before bed resolve use
...a natured video its microsoft content?
If you want to you can navigate in as...media...back.
...playing in india because I love this video so much
...my favorite is the...and anyways ccc have a
...nicely innovation kind of plays in here for the element actually coming
in you have your button cite here the way the buttons actually build...from center out
...in the future will be getting a dot-dot-dot more incorporated in their to
...have an actual spill over menu containment...you can add additional elements
...the flexibility in
...to from if you're going from phone of course you have five items that are actually
listen underneath for the double stack single-a courses...three
...based on sizing if you go with the most minimal size of an actual phone and then of course
it kind of extends and grows outward it to the
...you can have actually incorporated in their based on the device the spill over, you know,
course contains logically through that so,
here's the buttons kinda highlighted in that as well which onto it.
...click to how can we also thumbnail
and illustrate that before we do have also have thumbnails proper as well that were baking and
...you guys can actually, actually access
...be a thumbnail is...if you just want the tag for the actual scarborough as well.
...you...me and, then of course...just showing you as far as the title that xone
...as well as.
The amount of time remaining for the items and the
...items that a person might want actually, you know,
leverage or using watch.
...real quick
...switch to thephone ...just take a quick look at this.
Fantastic thank you all right so this is the fifth back-up I just want
to know had another phone up here so we came up prepared and,
remembered set the context were talking about the creator section right on tv details on
pc and how...and then on tv?
For...into.
The tv details...because of the
relevant panel individual state triggers the creators...
and critics reviews actually just re flow as you would expect on phone...
So, after seeing all these really great pieces of
...sample I want to open up to you guys as far as where you guys
want actually take it you know,
there's...possible these as far as how this actually can be leveraged...you could use
it as an actual tv or movie app media app you know, and,
get many users to one actually go there is the first-place or you could
actually turn into a creative marketplacecells and
inspires to crafting creators you know,
with the potential to have fans who might be really into retro
...green typewriters as well.
Or you could create an education
app that really brings the joy of any language someone or even
creates the opportunity to enhance someone to have better habits...their life.
Or even opportunity to just create something social this
whole use across all the different devices ultimately it's really up to
you it's all possible and I really can't wait to see where you guys take it.
Thank you limit.
Ok, so, as...we've been working together very closely...few
months as a developer design team focus on this template so you know,
my question was while I first saw this designs
...there's a low bar.
There's a high bar and then there's the matter bar has the if actually
call annette alamo working togetherhigh very hi, bar that lynette sets
...designs...we tackled these both in...js and jam or I focus
...js because I've been working with quite a bit previously with xbox and anand to the
in the audiencefocus on example version we collaborated together to add to put these
three to build these applications well, what I wanted...good so, one of the
question to ask is has again as we think about tackling this...man,
you know, universe what is platform sounds awesome but then it gets real your
...visual studio...looking all these platforms...thinking man?
It seems is a little...intimidating but as you probably learn in
all your sessions being a...you've heard about auc and build all the great technology that universal
into platform...make this as easy as possible we've had some dev nodes as we've gone along and
registers drive into little bit more but...a developer
...several questions like how do you think about your app how you structure your app you have universal is
...which works is guaranteed to work across all universe when
a plateau you have universal...a platform...what I'm trying to say
the api several work all across all of the universe window platform...
device form factors pleasure idea in you ready to build you're right you know-how
do you how you organize like really...package it...of the questions that you might ask are
...build separate app for every platform that's one way to
...try to build a single app across that works all across platforms sounds hard but
...as I've learned my experience in a sciences...working on
...version...not as hard
as a page is in has been in the past for sure with the universe was platform?
Ok, great through so.
You have a lot of options your out,
you know, I think by the for you might want to consider your app should be one binary the one
Package that runs across the entire platform
...definitely want to the couple the app from the os you wanted to be able to have
your app run and degree gracefully when it needs to if a part of
...if a user happens to be an older version of
...you wanted...degrade positively
are not degrade by improve positively enable and light
...the features that you've added on the target more recent versions of the understand platform
and...dive into it a little bit here I...want to take advantage of the device
specific sections sure...the api...across
...platforms it's a great capability and it really simplifies
...tremendously but you still want to build that
best experience who won all meet the nether bar and build an application thatworks
...with the default platform and it takes advantage of each of the features that
the platforms offer as a as ...diverse merge samples
...a second the media have sample is a single app there's a you know,
when gs version that will run across the platforms the same,
for example,...you notice...I tried I tried to
...we had a predeployed on phones is backups but when I have rhinos in here
...the emulator switch into the devices the same set of code is running across the platform
...we try to build...possible for two reasons one has
an ivory provide feedback to the engineering feature team and platform
...and give them feedback as are building and...learning together and...want,
you know, really test it out so that we you get the samples that there you
...samples not production code but there's real as possible...you know,
get into a sample?
Without adding a lot of complexity of like back-end...things like that so
responsive ui techniques, for example, we have the adaptive controls as you probably of
...previous sessions where I think the
...example session was a great session where the presenter showed
context menu invoked by a mouse...context
may look like your standard windows context menu without doing anything in the app if
you uses finger to touch-screen context menu where displayed based on
types you is bigger find a little bit more space around you get that
...free as part of the or is that esri but as part of the ...is platform
...that...built for...we also have the
read relative panel which is what we demonstrated with the creator section
how to automatically re flowed the ui base on which platform you're running on you use
design states to have...said say seven twenty pi so that when you're out so when
your application is running on a tablet that has maybe a few less pixels
that your app runs really well on that layout and sort of re
flows to content as needed?
We also platform we have
common input handling as I mentioned in the context many sample you don't have
to use a different control or do anything as a developer to support touch you know,
...you just get it with the platform same with xbox
...you summary size using the
controller interact with the same controls the same code the same api
...on xbox and it just worked now we do have some
...production code in the expected version just
...enabling to be able to show to today where we're going we're thinking but
... when we ship...have that all built-in for you?
Some responsive ui techniques for javascript the app
...spartan I should add a...something
...the edge browser essentially is the engine for the javascript applications that run on the
universe windows platform...get all the great benefits at the
...browser provides it's essentially the browser control hosted in a process as I mentioned all the
xbox one apps today or when gs apps and also many...media
...platforms across other a on other platforms and other devices also
javascript basis very common for media development to be web base so for media
applications particularly useful to have it in the javascript html
...accessory so these you...take advantage of with?
The web programming model for windows and I don't want to say
...js too much because I want you to think you have to use when js
you do not I've done development on xbox with the web
developer model available their and leverage...query
knockout js I've added you can, you know, you can add voice commands
to simple html five elements by just pulling in a little bit...gs to do
think...is just you know, another...leverage...so do you keep that in mind
...can use the very different our web frameworks let's see so
responsive you I techniques for api...works across both
the example and the web programming model so yes in
the web programming model you have the full windows runtime api is available to you can build csharp
...you can build a
csharp or cplus-plus windows runtime library and call that from
...library of your javascript app you can also have your javascript
app this into advance from csharp or cplus-plus.
Windows runtime library so that's why I just have a single site here has a works across the
...of the a ui development platforms...have so the use of
...take advantage of the responsive ui techniques...when
you want to build the best experience possible for the given platform.
Now on...windows application you have a back button on the screen
in the upper left-hand corner well on windows phone you know,
you have less pixels you have less screen real-estate you don't want to have a virtual
...or, you know, if you can avoid it not have a ...on-screen have the hardware
backbone so when they come examples you'll hear probably heard it may potentially
another sessions depending...such as you attended is a you check for the api for the hardware
...if it's there, you know,
don't show the...just take advantage of the hardware by nys
built on a platform I given extract example and xbox we have the one guide
how if you play with that channels if you played with you know, the live channel features of
...not with the one guy that is a great feature for media application which is
...talking about today so you probably want to...in as api zing...light up
those features when you are running your application your media application on xbox
so by checking for the presence of a type in your code allows
...apt to run a effectively across all the platforms and kind of,
you know, target in maintain that goal of having...single application work
on each platform...the...to be the best experience for each platform?
...a limited time and media player control because this...is a media application we have
...control that wraps a media element on
...gs or I should say the web programming model the web program model
...the video tag and provides a
lot features and really this is one of the times
one of the places where you would probably want to use
...js senior...programming model
base windowsuniverse windows app the reason why is because there's a lot of code in the media
...functionality that lynette covered so we kind of
...that for you that's a great time very that's a great example where...I will even
I love maybe...query or you jake for
...astral...great web programming frameworks out there...going to leverage
when jazz framework to say get media playback to just to our work really, really well in
the programming model the media player control prize all the features of...premium media application experience
you could leverage in...app a lot your news video in news apps this huge
...not just...like to watch what's going on with video when it comes to the news so,
don't just think that this applies to meet application as lynette and mention as well so,
there's twenty or twenty media can panthers...commanders puts all the inputs
...support an...cramming x completely template
...customize and theme both...gs version of...control?
Little bit on...video pipeline to touch on it for a completeness...media
...great session is that you should...deep dive into this dedicated to the video pipeline
so won't...diverted two-a-two deeply is the highlight that we do have
...the platform...we have...pay for dash and,
others can be added through third parties or you can write yourself to fried support so just a quick
...what's available...definitely more if you don't see a kodak
or format the gino's...just because I didn't make it complete I
...so if you have questions on it feel free to come up after the session
...the other sessions are really deep dive into what we support.
Right so we do have...sample we've been damn it as we've gone through or spend a little bit
of time with it and also just explain to some of the ways say from a
developers spectrum and how the template can help you out?
So, make the mediad sample your own sort of our theme iswhat I do to get this template
run...working...switch to...my pc?
That's good.
we've seen the ...seen at that we've democratic quite a bit so which is great because of
kind of set the context you seen the app work you seen lynette interact with it
talk to-you about it so I don't really have to do that part I'm going to focus in on
...sort of our philosophy with the samples and, how we how we one approach them so?
Here is the media
...template example this happens to be the wind the ingest version...
the samba version will be design the same way where, you know, I just want to make,
you know, I only want to change it as much as I need to do...get it up and running...sort of show
...my management and I'm going to customize it my every layout the tiles
...you know, make it really, really beautiful for a what are
...your designers design for is what you'll be able to do with it so I'm...going to run it real quick.
This version of it so that's the version you've been seeing now
many switch to another version what I did was...essentially
grab the gc rss feed.
From the.
From channel
nine from the twenty fifteen gcevent and it's going to run this here.
And, I left some of the old content in place just so you can
...you get to memory points here.
...my demo and I am are very...so we shall see and run here in a second
...so here's the same app that we've been demo ing I can you see the
...so their course we want to remove that for
a channel nine here is the you know, you want to may...read name
the carousel from movies too more focus on web video where video
slow the simpler than you're sort of for media...here like, you
know, the carousel works it shows a different
episode the animation works for the title and, a to the does
...you expected to do the list again if you navigate to less
...and go into it at all if you get a...page
will see...the browse page just kind of worked and all the content is listed
there how much work that I have to do to make this happen that's who I'm talking about a second this is again
...approach for both platforms and if isolate and item in the or if I go back to.
If I...down pick...item off of the this here.
And, there's details page so again we left unless somebody here
...spent about twenty minutes to make this happen was a lot of time at all but you know,
this would obviously you just remove this hub section from it the trailers again
...is populated...the take to build this out so what I what we did is.
We try to isolate the app sample as much as possible from
like are code and that was something we did with
xbox one over bringing it forward to the universal...is platform we
...out the samples is that once you to be able to just get up and running you're not going to
ship that we know that but you just want to get it up and running get a feel for the platform...learn
...as fast as possible so with that...I did was a added
...class this upper-class apologizes
send it'll do a get or...sample kind of idea so I just call this
class usually for your api...you're going to have standard headers and cookies and, you know,
authentication and things...every web call that you see this kind of isolated calls but at the end
...day you just going to is just calling x hr which is a xml http
requests call-in javascript so we see is coherent channel nine that data
that services all is doing is calling sh are under the covers so I'm going to go to...my
...data provider now the...it for this for the sample it's all baked into the
sample to keep it simple...usable fast you can run on an airplane if you
don't have wi-fi on your planar if you're not connected as I go to the
...data jsthe data generally wisconsin is files as just a bunch of
...so feature movie data is sample
sneaky tv episodes xr...so to show you that because what I did
is I took the data provider and I added
...channel nine data that services that saying get
requests to a url for the rss feed I get back so,
it's...rss feeds...json it's not ideal your json as faster
...parsemost data fees are says but I show you xml is
giving idea of how the data provided data model works so we make the call the
promise comes back the asic requests essentially comes
back we get the feed data let me ...celebrate point here...break points.
So, we hit the break points.
Me get to it.
So,...debate point so here's the add the javascript
...window images clear all this alps.
...f ten I do feed up's.
So, I think that's kind of cool javascript is images code
...run in the app it's pretty awesome...by the way I'm a huge...guy allows
...of windows phone for three years I did sample for excise
...the...a few books on top of to so
...and csharp it's awesome we will have this for that version but I would this one
...this particular sample...little far along in terms of this architecture so that's I'm showing
to javascript but it's always good the see more so,
here's a feed data if I dump it into the javascript consul.
You'll see it's an array of nodes I can expand
...I can see what I'm what I'm getting back here what I'm going to if I...down
...is...rss feed parse out as a node so what I'm going to do
...if I if I scroll up on the data provider just
a little bit you'll see the movie section of the data provider has
a data model declared what happens is I call the
rss feed I get the fourteen items from the are...feedback
...bellicose ninety-nine art...I did the...so we get the ffourteen adders for the
are says feedback each item is the little said chunk of
And, what I do is with the data model that's
...here for each item the data model is applied to that item
with that item does it takes the it takes the xml it
turns it into json since we have a sort of standard
json data model if you will that we use in media template
...up features for the platform for different platforms so we do is
you convert your...you use a data...convert your
feed information into this data model that runs within the app...the ideas...
sort of light up like...controls on xbox one as we do today on xbox want
to bring that forward to universal...platform?
a will now open up the data model for movies
Notice I having touched a page yet just remember that I showed you...demo I showed you what
it does haven't...page yet so I'm going to go into the are there data models?
And, I will.
Scroll up to description
...going to separate point here so we think of vita on when you see hit this
break point when I when I run I hate to break point this is one of those fifteen
...items some anurag clear this out again.
And,...going to don t item into.
The javascript x expand the edge of consul.
...scroll up you see descriptions right there so it's...coded up file write-up
...line-item say query
selector and then I'll just throw in description in air.
And, let's see we get back so...get back to get
back to the chunk of xml I don't want the angle brackets...so I
...get rid of that somebody's go ahead and then triad text contact...type
...see what's available I have the text content...
And, I don phillips.
I forgot those pesky periods...now let me jump this and now I'm
kind of where I'm at I got the description...now still not perfect I probably want to parse out the
p tag for the new and html system parsing
...field but you get the idea so that's with essentially the data model does
a little more complex for images sort-of so it's in our...of it may not have a thumb a
very size for every item xyz...web...so for the featured image
which is the big image that you see on the featured page or the carousel you know,
we try to use a...image possible so again...just a little query selectors to get in there but
not really super important other...that all I'm doing is taking xml
...into this standard json model and that's all I do to get this to work
there's no other coding require why the reason why is...just stick to our...
are metadata model if you follow that pattern then everything just...and has a touch any
the pages on a to get into any the code on...pages kind of just gated working
and then once you have a working from there you make it the best experience on the platform?
So, call-to-action.
Let's take it...nearing taker...okay.
So, definitely if you want to follow us on twitter you can with the uw
key design untruthful out the session
surveys we indicated earlier and there and I'm going backwards which is fine and,
you can of course review the other sessions that are available channel nine
that were provided and, then the actors authority...building amazing experiences
...uw...figure...retention advertising...
How...definitely taking questions unless, you know, for those who are trying to run-off and catch a flight?
...pacers rb have a question guys step up to the mike feel free to do and will also
be expert zone for about an hour share after this session?
So, the samples were still building them as you probably notice
there definitely a ui...haven't met the ...
bar quite yet so we're cleaning the and coda we the goal is to have these
as soon as possible after build will have them before launch
...targeting may just the related just a little later in may.
Yet what I do is you follow us on twitter udp design will posted
there also put it we're going to will have oppose where all the other samples...for windows
...upon get help.